You Chi.
유 치.
You Chi?
당신은 치?
Wu Shiguang, ever since we were kids,
우시광, 우리는 어렸을 때부터
I've been your little tagalong.
나는 당신의 작은 따갈롱이었습니다.
I was your playmate.
나는 당신의 놀이 친구였습니다.
I left home with you
나는 당신과 함께 집을 떠났습니다
and braved danger with you.
당신과 함께 위험을 감수했습니다.
Why can't I remember it?
왜 기억이 나지 않습니까?
I even followed you to the Shilin Sect.
나는 당신을 따라 스린파까지 따라갔습니다.
Have you seen Wu Shiguang?
우시광(Wu Shiguang)을 보셨나요?
I've got something really fun to tell him.
그 사람한테 정말 재미있는 얘기를 할 게 있어요.
Master Dragon Deity?
마스터 드래곤 신?
He's busy. Don't bother him.
그는 바쁘다. 그를 괴롭히지 마십시오.
He's still got a lot to deal with.
그에겐 아직 처리해야 할 일이 많이 남아 있다.
The people at the Shilin Sect are all pretty nice.
스린종의 사람들 모두 꽤 친절해요.
You little weasel, keep that Shilin Sect token on tight.
너 작은 족제비야, Shilin Sect 토큰을 단단히 보관하십시오.
Or you'll be wiped out.
아니면 당신은 전멸될 것입니다.
But the Shilin Sect isn't my home.
하지만 석림종은 내 집이 아닙니다.
A weasel demon like me shouldn't be here.
나 같은 족제비 악마는 여기에 있어서는 안 됩니다.
Is that the Dragon Deity?
저게 용신인가?
-Look. -He has to be.
-바라보다. - 그래야 해요.
Even the demon hunter commander is standing behind him.
악마사냥꾼 사령관이라도 그 뒤에 서있습니다.
-He has to be. -That's right.
- 그래야 해요. -좋아요.
Exactly, he must be the Dragon Deity!
바로, 그는 용신임에 틀림없다!
Being here, I feel like I'm in a skin that doesn't belong to me.
여기에 있으면 정말 피부가 좋아진 것 같아요 그건 내 것이 아닙니다.
It's uncomfortable.
불편해요.
-Now you've got so many demon hunters -This is for you.
-이제 악마사냥꾼이 너무 많아요 - 이것은 당신을 위한 것입니다.
following you.
당신을 팔로우합니다.
Maybe you don't really need me anymore.
어쩌면 당신은 더 이상 내가 필요하지 않을 수도 있습니다.
I need to talk to you.
얘기 좀 해야겠어요
Commander Li wants to see me. Let's talk later.
리 사령관이 나를 만나고 싶어합니다. 나중에 얘기하자.
So,
그래서
I'm leaving, Wu Shiguang.
나는 떠난다, 우시광.
You idiot weasel.
멍청한 족제비야.
Formless Moon, hear my command.
형태 없는 달이여, 내 명령을 들어라.
Go.
가다.
Activate the Nuwa Formation
누와 진형 활성화
and reveal the Four Pillars
네 기둥을 드러내세요
that uphold the earth.
지구를 지탱하는 것.
Yes.
예.
Have you seen You Chi?
You Chi를 보셨나요?
-Wangyan! -Canyue.
-왕얀! -까뉴에.
Canyue!
까뉴에!
Canyue.
Canyue.
Stop her.
그녀를 멈춰라.
Wangyan,
왕옌,
what happened?
무슨 일이에요?
Jiu Ying…
지우 잉…
Jiu Ying isn't dead.
주영은 죽지 않았다.
He possessed Wuyi.
그는 Wuyi를 소유했습니다.
Do you remember
기억하시나요
the four divine trees that uphold the earth I told you about?
지탱하는 네 개의 신성한 나무 내가 말했던 지구?
The Tree of Water grew beneath the sea.
물나무는 바다 밑에서 자랐습니다.
Its trunk is now the throne in Formless Moon's main hall.
그의 트렁크는 이제 왕좌입니다 형태 없는 달의 메인 홀에서.
Go.
가다.
Yes.
예.
The Crying Elm, now reduced to a broken stump,
울고 있는 느릅나무 이제 부러진 그루터기로 축소되었습니다.
is the Tree of Earth.
대지의 나무입니다.
The Firefluff Tree hidden in the axle of Wei mansion's weaving workshop
차축에 숨겨진 반딧불나무 웨이 맨션의 직조 작업장
is the Tree of Fire.
불나무이다.
Why does Jiu Ying want to destroy the Four Pillars?
Jiu Ying은 왜 파괴하고 싶어합니까? 네 기둥?
He wants the earth to collapse,
그는 지구가 붕괴되기를 원해요
all living things to perish,
모든 생명체가 멸망할 것입니다.
and this world
그리고 이 세상
to be left with nothing but fear and despair.
아무것도 남지 않게 그러나 두려움과 절망.
Where is the Tree of Metal?
금속나무는 어디에 있나요?
The Shilin Sect's Golden Scale Tree
석림종의 황금비늘나무
is the Tree of Metal.
금속의 나무이다.
Good thing
다행이다
there is the Eternal Formation keeping them away.
영원한 형성이 있습니다 그들을 멀리하십시오.
No.
아니요.
Wuyi
우이
has a Shilin Sect token.
Shilin Sect 토큰이 있습니다.
TOKEN OF SCALES
저울의 토큰
Wu Shiguang, why haven't you come to find me?
우시광, 왜 안 됐어? 나를 찾으러 오셨나요?
If you don't show up today, I won't be so easy
오늘 안 오면, 난 그렇게 쉽지 않을 거야
to cheer up!
응원하다!
Ye Changsheng,
예 창성,
bring the nearby townsfolk into the Shilin Sect for protection.
근처 마을 사람들을 데려와 보호를 위해 Shilin 종파에 들어갑니다.
Yes.
예.
Hurry!
서두르다!
Watch your step!
발걸음을 조심하세요!
This way! Quick!
이쪽으로! 빠른!
Keep up!
계속해서!
-Be careful! Hurry! -Go!
-조심하세요! 서두르다! -가다!
SERVE THE SCALES, UPHOLD THE RIGHT
저울을 섬기고 권리를 지키세요
Move!
이동하다!
-Go! -Keep up!
-가다! -계속해!
Inside! Go!
내부에! 가다!
If the Four Pillars collapse completely,
네 기둥이 완전히 무너지면
heaven and earth, including the Shilin Sect, will topple.
하늘과 땅, Shilin Sect를 포함하여 무너질 것입니다.
We have to stop Jiu Ying,
Jiu Ying을 막아야 해요
but…
하지만…
Master Dragon Deity.
마스터 드래곤 신.
My soul I devote. Long live the dragon.
내 영혼을 바칩니다. 드래곤 만세.
Master Dragon Deity, we await your orders.
용신님, 당신의 명령을 기다립니다.
Members of the Formless Moon
형태 없는 달의 구성원
can draw on the elemental power of the Four Pillars.
원소의 힘을 끌어낼 수 있습니다 네 기둥
The possessed sisters will be much stronger and hard to defeat.
빙의된 자매 훨씬 더 강해지고 패배하기 어려울 것입니다.
Only spells that counter the pillars' elements
반격하는 주문만 가능 기둥의 요소
can oppose them.
그들에게 반대할 수 있습니다.
Mo Yuntan, your artifact, the Spirit Brush,
모윤탄, 당신의 유물, 영혼 브러시,
uses ink-based water magic.
잉크 기반의 물 마법을 사용합니다.
It can counter fire.
화재에 대응할 수 있습니다.
Leave the Firefluff Tree to me.
Firefluff Tree는 나에게 맡겨주세요.
The Crying Elm is the oldest tree,
울고 있는 느릅나무는 가장 오래된 나무입니다.
the ancestor of all trees.
모든 나무의 조상.
My artifact, Golden Resonance, counters wood. Perfect.
내 유물, 황금 공명, 카운터 나무. 완벽한.
My blade is a divine weapon left behind by a mountain demon.
내 칼날은 신성한 무기다 산요괴가 남긴 것.
For centuries, it'd drawn
수세기 동안
on the essence of the soil from the peak of Mount Nandang.
흙의 본질에 대하여 난당산 정상에서.
Earth counters water.
지구는 물에 대응합니다.
I'll handle the Formless Moon's Tree of Water.
무형의 달은 내가 처리할게 물의 나무.
That leaves the Golden Scale Tree.
그러면 황금비늘나무가 남습니다.
Hua Qi…
화기…
What, are you going to attack your sister?
뭐야, 언니를 공격할 거야?
It's Jiu Ying I'm going to strike at.
내가 공격할 사람은 Jiu Ying이다.
Give my sister back!
내 여동생을 돌려줘!
What happened?
무슨 일이에요?
You Chi,
유 치,
-leave. -No way.
-떠나다. -안 돼요.
How can I leave when you're like this?
네가 이럴 때 내가 어떻게 떠날 수 있니?
Hua Qi, I'm no healer.
Hua Qi, 나는 치료사가 아닙니다.
Is there any way I can help?
제가 도와드릴 수 있는 방법이 있나요?
Yes.
예.
Take my place
내 자리를 차지해
and save the Golden Scale Tree.
황금 비늘 나무를 저장하세요.
Save the Golden Scale Tree?
황금비늘나무를 구하시겠습니까?
How?
어떻게?
Should I catch bugs or water it?
벌레를 잡아야 할까요, 아니면 물을 주어야 할까요?
Always keep this token on you.
이 토큰을 항상 소지하세요.
Otherwise, the ancient formations all over the Shilin Sect
그렇지 않으면 고대 구조물 Shilin 종파 전체
will reduce you to ashes in an instant.
당신을 한 순간에 재로 만들 것입니다.
Remember.
기억하세요.
No matter what you are or how capable you are,
당신이 무엇이든 또는 당신의 능력
always give it everything you've got, and do your best.
항상 당신이 가진 모든 것을 제공하세요. 최선을 다하세요.
Only then can you have no regrets.
그래야 후회가 없을 수 있습니다.
A little weasel thinks he can fight a nine-tailed fox?
작은 족제비 생각 그 사람이 구미호와 싸울 수 있다고?
Haven't you heard?
못 들었어?
Fire counters metal.
화재 대응 금속.
Hua Qi,
화 치,
you're draining your power.
당신은 당신의 힘을 소모하고 있습니다.
Almost done, Master Dragon Deity.
거의 완료되었습니다, 마스터 드래곤 신님.
Hold on a little longer.
조금만 더 참으세요.
Wangyan!
왕옌!
Wangyan,
왕옌,
did you think I couldn't beat you?
내가 널 이길 수 없을 거라고 생각했어?
Shiguang.
시광.
You are the only one in this world I still can't let go of.
당신은 이 세상에 유일한 사람이에요 아직도 버릴 수가 없어요.
Though I am gone,
비록 나는 떠났지만,
the Star Stone remains.
스타스톤이 남아있습니다.
If you find yourself in dire straits one day,
자신을 발견하면 어느 날 극심한 곤경에 처하게 되었어요
it may yet help you once.
그래도 한 번은 도움이 될 수 있습니다.
But remember this.
하지만 이것을 기억하세요.
The Star Stone's power is too great.
스타스톤의 위력이 너무 대단해요.
Do not use it rashly.
함부로 사용하지 마십시오.
Master…
선생님...
"Heaven and earth tremble.
"하늘과 땅이 떨린다.
Chaos fills the world.
혼돈이 세상을 가득 채운다.
An old soul returns against time.
늙은 영혼이 시간을 거슬러 돌아온다.
A new moon reshapes the world."
새 달이 세상을 바꾼다."
"Heaven and earth tremble.
"하늘과 땅이 떨린다.
Chaos fills the world."
혼돈이 세계를 가득 채운다."
The last share of Chi Wen's Dragon Deity's Power
마지막 공유 Chi Wen의 용신의 힘
took Ji Ling's heart stone
Ji Ling의 하트 스톤을 가져갔습니다
to the Dragon Abyss.
드래곤 어비스로.
Perhaps thousands of years from now,
아마도 지금으로부터 수천년 후에
it may take human form.
인간의 모습을 취할 수도 있습니다.
"An old soul returns against time."
"늙은 영혼은 시간을 거슬러 돌아온다."
Hua Qi.
화치.
Go to the Dragon Abyss.
드래곤 어비스로 가세요.
Give me your hand.
손을 주세요.
Use my blood to activate the Star Stone illusion
활성화하려면 내 피를 사용하세요 스타 스톤 환상
and bring Ji Ling's heart stone inside.
Ji Ling의 하트 스톤을 안으로 가져 오세요.
Go, now.
지금 가세요.
All right.
괜찮은.
This…
이…
isn't my limit yet.
아직 내 한계는 아니야.
Do my best
최선을 다해
and leave no regrets!
그리고 후회하지 마세요!
You only know fire counters metal.
당신은 금속 방화 카운터만 알고 있습니다.
But do you know that ice counters fire?
하지만 얼음 카운터가 작동한다는 것을 알고 계십니까?
A fleeting moment in the mortal world
필멸의 세계에서의 찰나의 순간
is a thousand years in the illusion.
천년의 환상입니다.
Master Dragon Deity, I will bring Ji Ling back.
마스터 드래곤 신, 나는 Ji Ling을 다시 데려올 것이다.
Your weapon's gone, and you still won't give up?
무기가 사라졌어요 그런데 아직도 포기하지 않을 거야?
The blade's gone,
칼날이 없어졌어,
but I'm still here.
하지만 난 아직 여기 있어요.
Today, I am going to defeat you!
오늘은 내가 널 이겨낼 거야!
Who says
누가 말했어
a weasel
족제비
can't beat a nine-tailed fox?
구미호를 이길 수 없나요?
Wu Shiguang,
우시광,
this time,
이번에는
I… I didn't
난… 난 안 그랬어
hold you back.
당신을 잡아.
You'd better not
안 하는 게 좋을 것 같아
lock me inside the Cosmic Pouch again.
나를 다시 우주주머니 안에 가둬두세요.
"An old soul…"
"오래된 영혼…"
THE OLD DRAGON FALLS THE NEW DRAGON RISES
늙은 용의 폭포 새로운 용의 등장
"Returns against time."
"시간에 맞춰 돌아옵니다."
You're back.
당신은 돌아왔다.
I am.
그래요.
And
그리고
so are they.
그들도 마찬가지다.
Master.
주인.
Why are you all back?
왜 다들 돌아왔어?
Because Ji Ling has already awakened the people
왜냐하면 Ji Ling은 이미 사람들을 깨웠어
of the Formless Moon.
형태 없는 달의.
Wake.
깨어 있다.
Wang,
왕,
the Four Pillars have been corrupted by the evil energy inside Jiu Ying.
네 기둥이 손상되었습니다 Jiu Ying 내부의 사악한 에너지에 의해.
Only by sacrificing the Formless Moon power within us
희생하는 것만으로도 우리 안에 있는 형태 없는 달의 힘
can we cleanse that evil energy.
그 사악한 에너지를 정화할 수 있을까요?
The wrong was ours.
잘못은 우리의 것이었습니다.
Let us make amends ourselves.
우리 스스로 사과해보자.
Wang, we leave the rest to you.
왕, 나머지는 당신에게 맡깁니다.
Save this world
이 세상을 구하세요
we have guarded for a millennium.
우리는 천년 동안 지켜왔습니다.
What is it?
그것은 무엇입니까?
What did the Moon Summoning Pearl say?
달 소환 진주는 뭐라고 말했나요?
Nothing.
아무것도 아님.
The sisters have all come to their senses.
자매들은 모두 정신을 차렸습니다.
They're repairing the Four Pillars.
그들은 Four Pillars를 수리하고 있습니다.
The collapse has stopped.
붕괴가 멈췄습니다.
Looks like they're all restored.
모두 복원된 것 같습니다.
I'll check on the Golden Scale Tree.
황금비늘나무를 확인해 보겠습니다.
Be careful.
조심하세요.
I've got it covered here.
여기에서 다뤘습니다.
You're still alive?
아직 살아 있나요?
Too bad Lu Wuyi thought you were truly dead.
안타깝게도 Lu Wuyi는 생각했습니다. 넌 정말 죽었어.
She was so heartbroken
그녀는 너무 상심했어요
that even her soul scattered into nothing.
그녀의 영혼조차도 아무것도 아닌 것으로 흩어졌습니다.
Jiu Ying,
지우 잉,
you killed Wu.
네가 우를 죽였어.
Today,
오늘은
I will make sure your soul is utterly destroyed.
나는 확실히 할 것이다 당신의 영혼은 완전히 파괴되었습니다.
Lu Wuyi,
루 우이,
you woke up again?
또 일어났어?
I told you,
내가 말했잖아
the one who should get out
나가야 할 사람
is you.
당신입니까?
Wu.
우.
Ji,
지
Jiu Ying has been trying to take control.
Jiu Ying은 통제하려고 노력해 왔습니다.
do it.
그것을 해라.
Kill me.
나를 죽여라.
Since I was created, I've been controlled
나는 창조된 이후로 통제를 받아왔다
my whole life.
내 평생.
This time,
이번에는
I want to be my true self.
나는 진정한 나 자신이 되고 싶다.
Help me,
도와주세요
Ji.
지.
Form up.
양식을 작성하십시오.
Qisha of the Southern Dipper.
남두의 치샤(Qisha).
Tiantong of the Southern Dipper.
남두의 천통.
Pojun of the Northern Dipper.
북두칠성의 포준.
In positions!
위치에 있습니다!
Master.
주인.
You Chi.
유 치.
Wangyan,
왕옌,
I did great
잘했어
this time.
이번에는.
She said
그녀가 말하길
a weasel
족제비
couldn't beat a nine-tailed fox,
구미호를 이길 수 없었어요
but look,
하지만 보세요,
I still beat her.
나는 아직도 그녀를 이겼다.
I helped, didn't I?
내가 도왔지, 그렇지?
Oh, right.
아, 그렇죠.
Look.
바라보다.
I was
나는
so smart this time.
이번엔 정말 똑똑해.
Wu Shiguang
우시광
won't get to call me an idiot again.
다시는 나를 바보라고 부르지 않을 거예요.
Do you know?
당신은 알고 있나요?
Wu Shiguang always says
Wu Shiguang은 항상 이렇게 말합니다
that when danger comes,
위험이 오면
I'm the type to dig a hole and hide in it.
저는 구멍을 파고 그 안에 숨는 편이에요.
Before you came,
당신이 오기 전에
I was so sad,
너무 슬펐어요
because I was going to die here alone,
난 여기서 혼자 죽을 예정이었으니까
and no one would ever know.
그리고 아무도 알지 못할 것입니다.
Wu Shiguang
우시광
must think I ran away again.
내가 또 도망친 것 같아.
Oh, right.
아, 그렇죠.
Remember to tell him
그에게 꼭 말해주세요
that I…
나는...
I really…
난 정말...
really did my best. I did…
정말 최선을 다했습니다. 그랬어요...
I did my best.
나는 최선을 다했다.
You Chi. You Chi!
유 치. 유 치!
How?
어떻게?
Lu Wuyi's soul was unusually resilient.
Lu Wuyi의 영혼은 유난히 회복력이 뛰어났습니다.
I was never able to find a way to erase it completely.
난 결코 길을 찾을 수 없었어 완전히 지우려면.
I should thank you, Wu Shiguang.
고마워요, Wu Shiguang.
With your Dragon Deity's Power,
당신의 용신의 힘으로,
you wiped out the last trace of her soul
당신은 그녀 영혼의 마지막 흔적을 지웠어요
and let me own this body completely.
그리고 이 몸을 완전히 소유하게 해주세요.
Why won't Lu Wuyi's body die?
Lu Wuyi의 몸은 왜 죽지 않습니까?
HEAVEN AND EARTH TREMBLE CHAOS FILLS THE WORLD
하늘과 땅이 떨린다 혼돈이 세상을 가득 채운다
AN OLD SOUL RETURNS AGAINST TIME A NEW MOON RESHAPES THE WORLD
시간을 거슬러 돌아온 오래된 영혼 새로운 달이 세상을 바꾼다
The Oracle Stone is missing a piece.
Oracle Stone에 조각이 없습니다.
The Oracle Stone!
오라클 스톤!
Besides a fragment of Jiu Ying's spirit,
Jiu Ying의 정신 조각 외에,
a fragment of the Oracle Stone is in her too.
오라클 스톤의 조각 그녀 안에도 있어요.
Wu's body
우의 시체
was made from the flesh and blood of nine-tailed foxes.
살로 만들어졌다 그리고 구미호의 피.
It has the power of rebirth granted by the Formless Moon.
다시 태어나는 힘이 있어요 형태 없는 달이 부여한 것입니다.
If she also has the Oracle Stone's ever-living divine power,
오라클 스톤도 가지고 있다면 영원히 살아 있는 신성한 힘,
then…
그럼...
Is there really no other way?
정말 다른 방법은 없을까?
"An old soul returns against time.
"오래된 영혼이 시간을 거슬러 돌아온다.
A new moon reshapes the world."
초승달이 세상을 바꾼다."
A new moon…
새로운 달이 떴다…
There is still one way.
아직 한 가지 방법이 있습니다.
And it's the only way.
그리고 그것이 유일한 방법입니다.
You've thought of it too.
당신도 그것을 생각했습니다.
What is it?
그것은 무엇입니까?
Turn back time
시간을 되돌려
and go back to the past
그리고 과거로 돌아가
to stop Lu Wuyi from ever being born.
Lu Wuyi가 태어나는 것을 막기 위해.
In other words,
즉,
erase Lu Wuyi's existence completely.
Lu Wuyi의 존재를 완전히 삭제하십시오.
Didn't Lonescale tell you?
론스케일이 말하지 않았나요?
The recent past of a few days can be changed.
최근 며칠간의 일 변경될 수 있습니다.
But Lu Wuyi was born 50 years ago.
하지만 Lu Wuyi는 50년 전에 태어났습니다.
To go back that far and change the past?
그렇게 먼 곳으로 돌아가 과거를 바꾸려면?
A fool's dream.
바보의 꿈.
"A new moon reshapes the world."
"새 달이 세상을 바꾼다."
Since the Oracle Stone gave such a prophecy,
오라클 스톤 이후 그런 예언을 했어
it means
그것은
this is destined to happen.
를 의미한다 이것은 일어날 운명이다.
I was a fallen star from beyond the heavens.
나는 떨어진 별이었어 하늘 너머에서.
I'm not bound by the laws of this world.
나는 이 세상의 법칙에 얽매이지 않습니다.
There was one question
질문이 하나 있었습니다
I spent my whole life pondering.
나는 평생을 고민하며 보냈습니다.
Even after bitter years of cultivation, I could never solve it.
수년의 농사를 지은 뒤에도 나는 그것을 결코 해결할 수 없었다.
You bear extraordinary power from beyond the heavens.
당신은 놀라운 힘을 가지고 있습니다 하늘 너머에서.
Slaughter is not your only choice.
학살만이 유일한 선택은 아닙니다.
I hope that one day,
언젠가는
you'll find the true meaning of coming to this world
당신은 진정한 의미를 발견하게 될 것입니다 이 세상에 오는 것
after crossing
건너간 후
countless galaxies.
셀 수 없이 많은 은하계.
For the past thousand years, I have asked myself
지난 천년 동안, 나 자신에게 물어봤어
why I came to this world
내가 이 세상에 온 이유
and what
그리고 뭐
I could do for it.
나는 그것을 할 수 있었다.
Now I understand.
이제 이해합니다.
After I crossed the galaxies and came to this world,
은하계를 횡단한 후 그리고 이 세상에 왔어,
I brought disaster upon it
내가 재앙을 가져왔어
and gave rise to Jiu Ying.
그리고 Jiu Ying을 낳았습니다.
So,
그래서,
it should be me who brings him to an end
그 사람을 끝내는 사람은 나여야 해
and saves this world.
그리고 이 세상을 구한다.